Wuqi **Zhang**

Also known as William Aaron Cheung Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science and Engineering

• Room 3663, Academic Building, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Clear Water Bay, Hong Kong

I am currently a Ph.D. candidate supervised by professor Shing-Chi Cheung at The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST) with a research focus: software engineering, especially in software testing and analysis. As a member of the CASTLE Research Group at HKUST, it is very nice to work with a professional and very kind professor, as well as a group of innovative researchers.

EDUCATION

2019 - Present Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering

CGA: 3.933/4.3

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong.

2015 - 2019 B.Eng. in Computer Science and Technology

GPA: 4.2149/5 (Rank: 1/250), Outstanding Graduates

Northeastern University, China

RESEARCH INTERESTS

RESEARCH FOCUS Software Engineering, Software Testing, Program Analysis
APPLICATION TO Blockchain, Smart Contracts, Decentralized Applications
OTHER INTERESTS Web Fingerprinting, Deep Learning System Testing

Publications

2022 Surakav: Generating Realistic Traces for a Strong Website Fingerprinting Defense

Conference Jiajun Gong, Wuqi Zhang, Charles Zhang, Tao Wang

In Proceedings of the 43rd IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (IEEE S&P 2022), May 23-26, 2022, San

Francisco, United States.

Fast Test Input Generation for Finding Deviated Behaviors in Compressed Deep Neural Network

Preprint Yongqiang Tian, Wuqi Zhang, Ming Wen, Shing-Chi Cheung, Chengnian Sun, Shiqing Ma, Yu Jiang arXiv:2112.02819

01/11/2112.02013

2021 WFDefProxy: Modularly Implementing and Empirically Evaluating Website Fingerprinting Defenses

Preprint Jiajun Gong, Wuqi Zhang, Charles Zhang, Tao Wang

arXiv:2111.12629

2021 DArcher: Detecting On-Chain-Off-Chain Synchronization Bugs In Decentralized Applications

Conference Wuqi Zhang, Lili Wei, Shuqing Li, Yepang Liu, Shing-Chi Cheung

In Proceedings of the 29th ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the

Foundations of Software Engineering (ESEC/FSE '21), August 23-28, 2021, Athens, Greece.

2021 Characterizing Transaction-Reverting Statements in Ethereum Smart Contracts

Conference Lu Liu, Lili Wei, Wuqi Zhang, Ming Wen, Yepang Liu, Shing-Chi Cheung

In Proceedings of the 34th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering (ASE

'21), November 14-20, 2021, Melbourne, Australia.

2018 Exploration on the Reform of Laboratory Integrated Management System in Colleges and Universities

Journal Wuqi Zhang, Xingyu Wang, Yi Sha, Lili Zhang

Research and Exploration in Laboratory, 2018, 37(11): 149-152.

P Awards

2019 Postgraduate Studentship

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

2019 Outstanding Graduates of Liaoning Province

Department of Education of Liaoning, China

2018 Second-class University Scholarship

Northeastern University, China

2018 Excellent Student Award

Northeastern University, China

2017 National Scholarship

Ministry of Education of the People's Republic of China

2017 First-class University Scholarship

Northeastern University, China

2017 Pacemaker to Excellent Student Award

Northeastern University, China

2016 National Scholarship

Ministry of Education of the People's Republic of China

2016 First-class University Scholarship

Northeastern University, China

2016 Pacemaker to Excellent Student Award

Northeastern University, China



2021-2022 Fall Teaching Assistant for COMP3021 Java Programming, HKUST

2020-2021 Spring Teaching Assistant for COMP5111 Fundamentals of Software Analysis, HKUST

2020-2021 Fall Teaching Assistant for COMP3021 Java Programming, HKUST

I VISITING EXPERIENCE

Research | The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong, China

2019

> Topic : Vulnerability Detection in Ethereum Smart Contracts

> Adviser: Professor Shing-Chi Cheung

> March, 2019 - May, 2019

Research Internship

Research North Carolina State University, NORTH CAROLINA, U.S.A.

2018

> Topic: Multiple Peaks Phenomenon in Non-Markovian Epidemics on Multilayer Networks

> Adviser: Professor Huaiyu Dai

> July, 2018 - August, 2018

Summer Research Program

WORK EXPERIENCE

2020-2021

Engineering | Hong Kong Applied Science and Technology Research Institute (ASTRI), Hong Kong, China

This is a joint project between ASTRI and Crypto-FinTech Lab of HKUST to develop the next-generation distributed file system based on blockchain and distributed computing technologies.

> October 2020 - June 2021 Blockchain FinTech Smart Contracts

Engineering | Shenyang Wuzhi Technology Co., Ltd., LIAONING, China

2018-2019

The company was funded by alumni of Northeastern University. The work in this company was to develop the back-end server of the mobile application that automatically translates sign language to Chinese.

> October 2018 - January 2019

RESTful Service | Sever-side Development

Engineering | Publicity Department of Northeastern University, LIAONING, China 2015-2019 | The work is to continuously maintain various University websites a

The work is to continuously maintain various University websites as one of the technical leaders in the student association.

> October 2015 - June 2019 Web Development RESTful Service